[English subtitles are available]
[الترجمة الإنجليزية متوفرة]
[Pretty Guardian of the City]
[الحارس الجميل للمدينة]
[Episode 1]
[الحلقة 1]
[Cangyue City]
[مدينة كانغيو]
This is
هذا هو
the map of Lord Zhang's Hot Spring Villa.
خريطة فيلا اللورد تشانغ في الينابيع الساخنة.
Here.
هنا.
If we dig down forty or fifty meters,
إذا حفرنا أربعين أو خمسين مترا ،
we can definitely find the mouth of the hot spring.
يمكننا بالتأكيد أن نجد فم الينابيع الساخنة.
This is the map
هذه هي الخريطة
of Master Liu's tomb.
قبر السيد ليو.
The graveyard must be
يجب أن تكون المقبرة
in the southeast of the city.
في جنوب شرق المدينة.
The land is on the dragon whiskers.
الأرض على شوارب التنين.
Although it's feeble,
على الرغم من أنها ضعيفة ،
it still can get some dragon aura.
لا يزال بإمكانه الحصول على بعض هالة التنين.
My name is Luo Xiyun.
اسمي لوه شييون.
I was born with the poison of heartburn，
ولدت بسم حرقة الفؤاد ，
and I have experienced many changes in the world.
وشهدت العديد من التغييرات في العالم.
I disguised myself as Yunxi for the last eight years
لقد تنكرت بزي يونكسي خلال السنوات الثماني الماضية
and lived secretly in Jianjia Alley.
وعاش سرا في Jianjia Alley.
With the ancestral skill of mapping,
مع مهارة الأجداد لرسم الخرائط ،
I've become the most popular folk cartographer
لقد أصبحت رسام الخرائط الأكثر شعبية
in Cangyue City.
في مدينة كانجيو.
No wonder that the roof is sinking.
لا عجب أن السقف يغرق.
The proportion of the roof is wrong.
نسبة السقف خاطئة.
The ratio of the upper cornice and the eave column
نسبة الكورنيش العلوي وعمود الإفريز
should be three to ten.
يجب أن يكون من ثلاثة إلى عشرة.
Otherwise, it won't be stable.
خلاف ذلك ، لن يكون مستقرًا.
The master of Cangyue City has an order.
سيد مدينة كانغيو لديه أمر.
From now on,
من الان فصاعدا،
we begin the construction project
نبدأ مشروع البناء
for the whole Cangyue City
لمدينة كانغيو بأكملها
The project concerns the foundation of
يتعلق المشروع بتأسيس
Cangyue City in future generations.
مدينة كانجيو في الأجيال القادمة.
Each shop
كل محل
should strictly follow the city's construction policy.
يجب أن تتبع بدقة سياسة البناء في المدينة.
Although we only get to know each other
على الرغم من أننا نتعرف فقط على بعضنا البعض
for a short time,
لمدة قصيرة،
we're still close.
ما زلنا قريبين.
I treat you like my brother.
أنا أعاملك مثل أخي.
I am determined to
أنا مصمم على
win the competition today.
الفوز بالمسابقة اليوم.
I can only accept success but not failure.
يمكنني فقط قبول النجاح وليس الفشل.
Training troops for a thousand days,
تدريب القوات لألف يوم ،
I'll use them for today.
سأستخدمهم لهذا اليوم.
Ham.
لحم خنزير.
I'm counting on you today.
أنا أعتمد عليك اليوم.
Show me your manner as a general,
أرني أسلوبك كجنرال ،
and run fast.
وركض بسرعة.
You hear me?
هل تسمعني؟
I know you understand.
أنا أعلم أنك تفهم.
Come on.
هيا.
Go! Go! Go!
يذهب!  يذهب!  يذهب!
Go! Go!
يذهب!  يذهب!
[The fifth Pig Competition of Cangyue City]
[مسابقة الخنازير الخامسة لمدينة كانغيو]
Brother,
أخ،
you miused the power of the Chief Inspector
لقد استغلت سلطة رئيس المفتشين
to block the road to race pigs.
لقطع الطريق على سباق الخنازير.
I'm sure you'll be impreached
أنا متأكد من أنك سوف تشرب
by those old men.
من قبل هؤلاء الرجال المسنين.
Look at you.
انظر لحالك.
You know
أنت تعرف
we can't compare with you.
لا يمكننا المقارنة معك.
Who says I am racing pigs here?
من قال إنني أتسابق الخنازير هنا؟
I'm just training them.
أنا فقط أدربهم.
I'll let them
سوف أسمح لهم
to measure the length of Imperial Street
لقياس طول شارع إمبريال
so that I can plan the time for repair.
حتى أتمكن من التخطيط لوقت الإصلاح.
-You win. -You win.
-فزت.  -فزت.
I hereby announce
أعلن بموجبه
the fifth Pig Competition of Cangyue City
مسابقة الخنازير الخامسة لمدينة كانجيو
begins now.
يبدأ الآن.
Yes.
نعم.
Yeah!
نعم!
This is the Water Dragon from Prince Kang's Mansion.
هذا هو تنين الماء من قصر الأمير كانغ.
He's just
انه فقط
an ignorant playboy.
مستهتر جاهل.
He's good at playing with pigs and dogs.
يجيد اللعب مع الخنازير والكلاب.
He's good at playing around.
إنه جيد في اللعب.
He doesn't know anything about construction.
إنه لا يعرف أي شيء عن البناء.
It's just that the Master of Cangyue City
إنه فقط سيد مدينة كانغيو
wants to secure his position as the young master,
يريد أن يؤمن منصبه كسيد شاب ،
so he named him as the Chief Inspector.
لذلك عينه رئيس المفتشين.
Bravo! Bravo!
ولد جيد!  ولد جيد!
Next one, please.
التالي ، من فضلك.
There is a pig in Prince Jing's Mansion.
يوجد خنزير في قصر الأمير جينغ.
Kun is brave and its hooves are fast enough to generate wind.
كون شجاع وحوافره سريعة بما يكفي لتوليد الرياح.
Bravo.
أحسنت.
Brother!
أخ!
Yun'er, run!
يونير ، اركض!
Brother.
أخ.
Today,
اليوم،
I can avenge you.
يمكنني الانتقام لك.
Brother, it's an emergency.
أخي ، إنها حالة طارئة.
Take care of it for me.
اعتني بها من اجلي
Go!
يذهب!
My pig!
خنزير بلدي!
Say something.
قل شيئا.
This pig.
هذا الخنزير.
It's full of treasures.
إنها مليئة بالكنوز.
For example, the spine
على سبيل المثال ، العمود الفقري
can be stewed.
يمكن مطهي.
Yes.
نعم.
You can have a sauerkraut stewed pork bone.
يمكنك الحصول على عظم لحم الخنزير مخلل الملفوف.
and have aftertaste in your mouth.
ولديك مذاق في فمك.
The liver and kidney can be fried.
يمكن قلي الكبد والكلى.
Anyway,
على أي حال،
you can cook it in so many ways and all of them are delicious.
يمكنك طهيها بعدة طرق وكلها لذيذة.
Get off.
انزل.
Awesome!
رائع!
On your mark.
على علامتك.
Ready!
مستعد!
You're the best.
أنت الأفضل.
Come on, Ham.
تعال يا هام.
Ham is the first.
لحم الخنزير هو الأول.
Ham. Ham.
له.  له.
You are a good Ham.
أنت لحم خنزير جيد.
Come on.
هيا.
Kun.
متي.
Ham, go!
هام ، اذهب!
Bravo.
أحسنت.
Go!
يذهب!
To win the first prize, don't look back.
للفوز بالجائزة الأولى ، لا تنظر إلى الوراء.
Ham, run!
هام ، اركض!
Brother.
أخ.
I think you should give up.
أعتقد أنك يجب أن تستسلم.
The first prize this time
الجائزة الأولى هذه المرة
must belong to my Kun.
يجب أن تنتمي إلى كون بلدي.
Shut up.
اسكت.
Come on.
هيا.
Go! Go!
يذهب!  يذهب!
Run! Run!
يجري!  يجري!
Come on!
هيا!
This...
هذه...
Brother, you...
شقيق لك...
You are cheating!
انت تغش!
I am holding the competition,
أنا أقوم بالمسابقة ،
so I can make the rules.
حتى أتمكن من وضع القواعد.
What can you do about it?
ماذا يمكنك أن تفعل بهذا الشأن؟
Come on.
هيا.
It's flying!
إنها تطير!
Assassin!
قاتل!
Protect Young Master!
حماية السيد الشاب!
Jiang Chaoxi!
جيانغ شاوكسي!
Let me kill you!
دعني أقتلك!
What should we do?
ماذا علينا ان نفعل؟
Run!
يجري!
You...
أنت...
Who are you?
من أنت؟
Do you know it is the death penalty
هل تعلم أنها عقوبة الإعدام
to assassinate me?
لاغتيالي؟
Someone who wants to kill you.
شخص يريد قتلك.
The smell...
الرائحة...
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
Shameless!
وقح!
My Young Master.
سيدي الشاب.
Are you okay?
هل انت بخير؟
Where is she?
أين هي؟
Candied haws!
الزعرور المسكرة!
Jiang Chaoxi.
جيانغ تشوكسي.
I didn't kill you today.
أنا لم أقتلك اليوم.
I will take this pig as interest on money.
سأعتبر هذا الخنزير فائدة على المال.
I'm back.
لقد عدت.
[Jianjiang Alley]
[زقاق جيانجيانغ]
I heard that Old Li
سمعت أن Old Li
is sick again.
مريض مرة أخرى.
Sister, you're back.
أختي ، لقد عدت.
We are having a roasted pig today.
لدينا خنزير مشوي اليوم.
Sister Yun,
الأخت يون ،
you're so nice to us.
أنت لطيف جدا معنا.
It's almost burnt.
كادت أن تحترق.
Time to eat.
وقت الطعام.
Enough.
كافية.
[Eastern Mansion of Xiao'ao]
[قصر شياو آو الشرقي]
My Ham is gone.
ذهب لحم بلدي.
Whose Ham?
من لحم الخنزير؟
My precious racing pig.
خنزير السباق الثمين.
It must have been stolen.
يجب أن يكون قد سُرق.
Besides, who wants to kill me?
علاوة على ذلك ، من يريد قتلي؟
Who did I offend?
من أساءت؟
If you weren't so naughty,
إذا لم تكن شقيًا جدًا ،
how could the assassin
كيف يمكن للقاتل
get the chance to kill you?
الحصول على فرصة لقتلك؟
You are definitely not my uncle.
أنت بالتأكيد لست عمي.
I was assassinated.
لقد تم اغتيالي.
How can you say that to me?
كيف يمكنك أن تقول ذلك لي؟
Your uncle is right.
عمك على حق.
What did I ask you to do?
ماذا طلبت منك ان تفعل؟
The construction of Cangyue City.
بناء مدينة كانجيو.
And what did you do?
و ماذا فعلت؟
You used your power to indulge in playing around.
لقد استخدمت قوتك لتنغمس في اللعب.
You ask me to be in charge of the construction,
تطلب مني أن أكون مسؤولاً عن البناء ،
but I can't even understand a map.
لكني لا أستطيع حتى أن أفهم الخريطة.
You are making me do something entirely beyond me.
أنت تجعلني أفعل شيئًا يتجاوزني تمامًا.
Young Master,
المعلم الصغير،
You will be the Master of Cangyue City one day,
ستكون سيد مدينة كانغيو يومًا ما ،
so you need to make some achievements to pave your way in advance.
لذلك تحتاج إلى تحقيق بعض الإنجازات لتمهيد طريقك مسبقًا.
What's the Master of Cangyue City?
ما هو سيد مدينة كانغيو؟
I don't care.
لا أهتم.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
you don't need to inspect
لا تحتاج للتفتيش
the city's construction.
بناء المدينة.
Great.
رائعة.
Then you should behave yourself,
إذن عليك أن تتصرف ،
get married,
تزوج،
and have a baby as soon as possible.
وإنجاب طفل في أسرع وقت ممكن.
While I can still move,
بينما لا يزال بإمكاني التحرك ،
I'll personally cultivate your children.
سأقوم شخصيا بتربية أطفالك.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
So many girls.
الكثير من الفتيات.
Do you like anyone?
هل يعجبك احد
Mother,
الأم،
this painting is very realistic.
هذه اللوحة واقعية جدا.
But it lacks some lingering charm.
لكنها تفتقر إلى بعض السحر الباقي.
This paiting has a good artistic conception.
هذا الرهن له تصور فني جيد.
This...
هذه...
This is good.
هذا جيد.
[Royal Censor Zhang Zhiyuan's eldest daughter Zhang Hanyu]
[الابنة الكبرى للرقابة الملكية تشانغ تشي يوان تشانغ هانيو]
This painting is very rare.
هذه اللوحة نادرة جدا.
Exaggerated and unruly.
مبالغ فيها وجامحة.
No matter how distorted the character is,
بغض النظر عن مدى تشوه الشخصية ،
it has to present
يجب أن تقدم
her cute little face.
وجهها الصغير اللطيف.
I knew these vulgar women
كنت أعرف هؤلاء النساء المبتذلة
are not my son's type.
ليسوا من نوع ابني.
How about this one?
ماذا عن هذه؟
[Prince Xiao Huasheng's only daughter Xiao Fengyi]
[ابنة الأمير شياو هوا شنغ الوحيدة شياو فنجي]
This girl is lively and cute,
هذه الفتاة حيوية ولطيفة ،
as well as elegant and beautiful.
وكذلك أنيقة وجميلة.
Isn't this my cousin Fengyi?
أليس هذا ابن عمي Fengyi؟
Why are you
لماذا انت
so disobedient?
عاصي جدا؟
Madam,
سيدتي،
The Star Astronomy Bureau has predicted
توقع مكتب علم الفلك النجمي
the Young Master's destined girl.
الفتاة الموجهة للماجستير الصغير.
Who is she?
من هي؟
Is it Fengyi?
هل هو Fengyi؟
The Star Astronomy Bureau didn't say
لم يقل مكتب علم الفلك النجمي
who she is.
من هي.
But they inferred that
لكنهم استنتجوا ذلك
she would be saved three times by the Young Master.
سيتم إنقاذها ثلاث مرات من قبل السيد الشاب.
In other words, the so-called love for three saves.
وبعبارة أخرى ، فإن ما يسمى بالحب لثلاثة ينقذ.
love for three saves?
الحب لثلاثة يحفظ؟
Mother,
الأم،
since my marriage
منذ زواجي
is destined,
مقدر ،
let Feng Yi
دع فنغ يي
marry to someone else.
الزواج من شخص آخر.
Stop right there!
توقف هناك!
I must settle
لا بد لي من تسوية
your marriage with Fengyi today.
زواجك مع Fengyi اليوم.
Mother,
الأم،
I really have something urgent to do.
لدي حقا شيء عاجل لأفعله.
You see we haven't caught the assassin,
ترى أننا لم نقبض على القاتل ،
and found Ham yet.
ووجدت حام بعد.
If I stay longer,
إذا بقيت لفترة أطول ،
Ham will be well-cooked.
سيكون لحم الخنزير مطبوخًا جيدًا.
You...
أنت...
Look at him.
انظر اليه.
Have some meat.
تناول بعض اللحوم.
It smells so good.
رائحتها جيدة جدا.
It's pork.
إنه لحم خنزير.
I'll take this chunk.
سآخذ هذه القطعة.
Heiya.
هييا.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
They are choosing a wife for Young Master
إنهم يختارون زوجة للماجستير الصغير
in our Cangyue City.
في مدينة كانغيو.
Whether wealthy or poor,
سواء كانت غنية أو فقيرة ،
as long as the girl is saved three times by our Young Master,
طالما أن سيدنا الشاب أنقذ الفتاة ثلاث مرات ،
she'll be his destined one.
ستكون المصير له.
I'm going to be Young Master's wife.
سأكون زوجة يونغ ماسترز.
You little chick.
أنت كتكوت صغير.
Look at yourself.
انظر الى نفسك.
Young Master's wife?
زوجة السيد الشاب؟
You're in a daydream.
أنت في أحلام اليقظة.
It's better than
انها أفضل من
thinking about nothing all day.
أفكر في لا شيء طوال اليوم.
What if it comes true?
ماذا لو تحقق؟
It's all because of you.
كله بسببك.
Don't blame me for nagging.
لا تلومني على الإزعاج.
Even the fat girl and the skinny girl
حتى الفتاة السمينة والفتاة النحيلة
at the alley
في الزقاق
are proposed by others.
يقترحها آخرون.
Look at you.
انظر لحالك.
You always jump here and there,
أنت تقفز دائمًا هنا وهناك ،
living in the pile of men.
الذين يعيشون في كومة من الرجال.
Come.
يأتي.
Aunt Xu.
العمة شو.
I've just peeled the thigh meat.
لقد قشرت للتو لحم الفخذ.
Try it.
جربها.
Don't you think I'll let you off easily.
لا تعتقد أنني سأتركك بسهولة.
Come on. Eat it.
هيا.  كلها.
Uncle Jin, where's Xiao Qing?
العم جين ، أين شياو تشينغ؟
Why didn't you ask him to come over for meat?
لماذا لم تطلب منه أن يأتي للحوم؟
He's probably picking flowers right now.
من المحتمل أنه يقطف الزهور الآن.
Xiao Qing.
شياو تشينغ.
Didn't I tell you
ألم أخبرك
not to come to the back mountain during this season?
ألا تأتي إلى الجبل الخلفي خلال هذا الموسم؟
You know you will get rashes
أنت تعلم أنك ستصاب بالطفح الجلدي
if you touch the flowers.
إذا لمست الزهور.
Do you want to die?
هل تريد أن تموت؟
Where did you go today?
اين ذهبت اليوم؟
A client asked me to draw up
طلب مني أحد العملاء أن أرسم
a planning map of the villa.
خريطة تخطيطية للفيلا.
I went to measure it on site.
ذهبت لقياسه في الموقع.
Yunxi,
يونشى ،
we grew up together.
نشأنا معا.
You can't fool me.
لا يمكنك أن تخدعني.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Why did you assassinate Young Master?
لماذا اغتالت السيد الشاب؟
What are you talking about?
ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟
How could I kill him?
كيف يمكنني قتله؟
Don't think too much.
لا تفكر كثيرا.
I just roasted a pig.
أنا فقط شويت خنزير.
Let's go and eat the meat.
لنذهب ونأكل اللحم.
And these flowers
وهذه الزهور
should be brewed soon.
يجب أن يخمر قريبا.
I love
أنا أحب
the flower wine you made.
نبيذ الزهرة الذي صنعته.
[Notice for a missing pig]
[إشعار عن خنزير مفقود]
[It looks like this.]
[تبدو هكذا.]
Now it is put up
الآن يتم طرحه
all over the street.
في جميع أنحاء الشارع.
Besides, the assassination of the Young Master
الى جانب اغتيال السيد الشاب
is spread out everywhere.
منتشرة في كل مكان.
And you
وأنت
happened to bring back a pig today.
حدث لإعادة خنزير اليوم.
I just came across the pig
لقد مررت للتو عبر الخنزير
by accident.
بالصدفة.
Fine.
بخير.
Forget it if you don't want to tell me.
انسى الأمر إذا كنت لا تريد أن تخبرني.
I'll help you kill him.
سوف أساعدك على قتله.
If I fail,
إذا فشلت،
it's worth it to die for you.
يستحق أن تموت من أجلك.
Don't do anything stupid.
لا تفعل أي شيء غبي.
Fine.
بخير.
I am the assassin.
أنا القاتل.
But it's all a misunderstanding.
لكن كل هذا سوء فهم.
I didn't mean to kill him.
لم أقصد قتله.
I just want to
أريد فقط
marry him.
تتزوجه.
Marry him!
تتزوجه!
Rumor has it that the Young Master is going to get married.
تقول الشائعات أن السيد الشاب سوف يتزوج.
The girl saved three times by him
أنقذت الفتاة ثلاث مرات بواسطته
will be his destined wife.
ستكون زوجته.
So,
لذا،
I want to creat a dangerous situation
أريد أن أخلق وضعا خطيرا
for myself
لنفسي
so that he can save me.
حتى يتمكن من إنقاذي.
Why do you want to marry the Young Master?
لماذا تريد الزواج من السيد الشاب؟
I...
أنا...
Isn't it good to stay in our Jianjia Alley?
أليس من الجيد البقاء في Jianjia Alley؟
Yes, it's good.
نعم انها جيدة.
That's exactly why I want to marry
هذا هو بالضبط سبب رغبتي في الزواج
the most promising man
الرجل الواعد
in Cangyue City.
في مدينة كانجيو.
I can use my marriage
يمكنني استخدام زواجي
in exchange for a bright future
مقابل مستقبل مشرق
for everyone in Jianjia Alley.
للجميع في Jianjia Alley.
After all, wealth is coming out of danger.
بعد كل شيء ، الثروة تخرج من الخطر.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Let's not talk about this.
دعنا لا نتحدث عن هذا.
Look
نظرة
what I prepared for you.
ما أعددته لك.
Do you like it?
هل أحببت ذلك؟
I knew it.
كنت أعرف.
Xiao Qing
شياو تشينغ
looks the best in this.
يبدو الأفضل في هذا.
Stop.
قف.
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
The Imperial Street is a bit strange today.
شارع إمبريال غريب بعض الشيء اليوم.
It seems to have a murderous vibe.
يبدو أن لديها أجواء قاتلة.
Young Master, I'm here!
السيد الشاب ، أنا هنا!
Help!
مساعدة!
Young Master!
المعلم الصغير!
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
I think they're all here for you.
أعتقد أنهم جميعًا هنا من أجلك.
It's all because of my charm. Let's go.
كل هذا بسبب سحري.  لنذهب.
Hurry up.
عجلوا.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
Aunt.
عمة.
My goodness.
رباه.
This...
هذه...
So much money?
الكثير من المال؟
Aunt,
عمة،
take this money
خذ هذا المال
to improve the food quality
لتحسين جودة الطعام
for everyone.
للجميع.
Don't be so stingy.
لا تكن بخيل جدا.
When I was young,
عندما كنت صغيرا،
I ate too many radishes and vegetables,
أكلت الكثير من الفجل والخضروات ،
and I was always starving.
وكنت دائما أتضور جوعا.
Yunxi,
يونشى ،
you hid so much money.
لقد أخفيت الكثير من المال.
And it took you so long to take it out.
وقد استغرق الأمر وقتًا طويلاً لإخراجها.
Aunt.
عمة.
What's wrong with me giving you the money?
ما الخطأ في إعطائي المال؟
If you had taken it out earlier,
إذا كنت قد أخرجته في وقت سابق ،
I could buy you some expensive tonics.
يمكنني أن أشتري لك بعض المقويات باهظة الثمن.
And maybe your weak body
وربما جسدك الضعيف
have long been cured.
منذ فترة طويلة.
Yunxi,
يونشى ،
are you sick again?
هل انت مريض مرة اخرى
I'll go...
سأذهب...
I'll go find Dr. Qi.
سأذهب لأجد الدكتور تشي.
Yunxi, it's fine.
Yunxi ، لا بأس.
Come.
يأتي.
Yunxi.
يونشى.
Dr. Qi is here.
الدكتور تشي هنا.
Yunxi,
يونشى ،
I'll go cook.
سأذهب كوك.
Xiao Qing.
شياو تشينغ.
Yunxi.
يونشى.
Come and boil some water for me.
تعال واغلي بعض الماء من أجلي.
Thank you for your time, Dr. Qi.
شكرا لك على وقتك يا دكتور تشي.
You don't have to say thanks.
ليس عليك أن تقول شكرا.
Yunxi,
يونشى ،
you used the strong medicine
لقد استخدمت الدواء القوي
to suppress the poison of heartburn in your heart again, right?
لقمع سم الحموضة في قلبك مرة أخرى ، أليس كذلك؟
How many times have I told you?
كم مرة قلت لك؟
It can relieve pain,
يمكن أن يخفف الألم ،
but it just fights fire with fire.
لكنها تحارب النار بالنار فقط.
Those medicines will only deepen the toxin in your heart
ستعمل هذه الأدوية على تعميق السموم في قلبك فقط
and make your poison flare-ups more frequent.
ويجعل تفجر السموم أكثر تواترا.
How long can I live?
كم من الوقت يمكنني العيش؟
One year tops.
سنة واحدة قمم.
Or
أو
only six months left.
بقي ستة أشهر فقط.
That's enough.
هذا يكفي.
Father,
أب،
because of that love for three rescues,
بسبب هذا الحب لثلاثة عمليات إنقاذ ،
the whole city's girls
فتيات المدينة كلها
are waiting for me to save them.
ينتظرونني لإنقاذهم.
What should I do?
ماذا علي أن أفعل؟
Just choose one and marry her.
فقط اختر واحدة وتزوجها.
Everyone will be happy.
سيكون الجميع سعداء.
Do you think I'm you?
هل تعتقد انني انت
I mean,
أعني،
getting married now will distract me
الزواج الآن سيشتت انتباهي
and hold me back,
وتراجعني ،
affecting the construction of Cangyue City.
تؤثر على بناء مدينة كانغيو.
It's fine.
لا بأس.
So that you won't say
حتى لا تقول
I always force you in the future.
أنا دائما أجبرك في المستقبل.
Besides,
بجانب،
you can't even
لا يمكنك حتى
read the map.
اقرأ الخريطة.
I can learn!
يمكنني التعلم!
Who dares to teach you now?
من يجرؤ على أن يعلمك الآن؟
Nonsense.
كلام فارغ.
Cangyue City is full of talents.
مدينة كانجيو مليئة بالمواهب.
People from other cities
أناس من مدن أخرى
are also lining up to teach me.
يصطفون أيضًا لتعليمي.
You don't have to worry about that.
لا داعي للقلق بشأن ذلك.
Now I've made up my mind.
الآن لقد اتخذت قراري.
I will do my best
سأبذل قصارى جهدي
to build Cangyue City
لبناء مدينة كانجيو
till my heart ceases to beat.
حتى يتوقف قلبي عن الخفقان.
Well I don't have to sacrifice my life.
حسنًا ، لست مضطرًا للتضحية بحياتي.
Fine.
بخير.
I'll give you one more chance.
سأعطيك فرصة أخرى.
Really?
هل حقا؟
I don't believe
أنا لا أعتقد
I can't teach you a lesson.
لا أستطيع أن أعلمك درسا.
You must keep
يجب أن تحتفظ به
this jade comb.
مشط اليشم.
Brother!
أخ!
Yun'er, run!
يونير ، اركض!
Brother.
أخ.
I will kill Jiang Chaoxi
سأقتل جيانغ تشاوكسي
to avenge you!
للانتقام لك!
Wonderful.
رائع.
Chicken is chicken, and duck is duck.
الدجاج دجاج والبط بطة.
The monkey is wearing a flower.
القرد يرتدي زهرة.
This painting is honored to have been verified by you.
نتشرف بأن تكون هذه اللوحة قد تم التحقق منها بواسطتك.
Its value will be greatly increased.
سيتم زيادة قيمتها بشكل كبير.
By the way,
على فكرة،
have you found Luo Hexuan?
هل وجدت لوه هيكسان؟
Master,
يتقن،
We haven't found anything
لم نعثر على أي شيء
about him yet.
عنه حتى الان.
Rest assured, Master.
اطمئن يا معلمة.
This time, during the demolition and construction of the city,
هذه المرة ، خلال عمليات الهدم والبناء في المدينة ،
we can count all households.
يمكننا عد جميع الأسر.
As long as Luo Hexuan is in Cangyue City,
طالما أن Luo Hexuan في مدينة Cangyue ،
we will find him.
سنجده.
It's been eight years.
لقد مرت ثماني سنوات.
I've been waiting for too long.
لقد كنت أنتظر طويلا.
Those who obtain the Fengchi will live forever.
أولئك الذين يحصلون على Fengchi سيعيشون إلى الأبد.
As long as we find Luo Hexuan,
طالما وجدنا لوه هيكسان ،
we can find Fengchi.
يمكننا أن نجد Fengchi.
This is
هذا هو
my lifelong pursuit.
سعيي مدى الحياة.
Master,
يتقن،
we've been looking for him for so long,
كنا نبحث عنه منذ فترة طويلة ،
but we haven't found him.
لكننا لم نعثر عليه.
Could it be that Luo Hexuan and his sister
هل يمكن أن يكون ذلك لوه هيكسان وأخته
are dead?
ماتوا؟
I don't care.
لا أهتم.
Even if he dies, I want to see his body.
حتى لو مات ، أريد أن أرى جسده.
Luo Hexuan
لوه هيكسان
knows a lot of my secrets.
يعرف الكثير من أسراري.
Besides,
بجانب،
I sent so many people to look for him
لقد أرسلت الكثير من الناس للبحث عنه
but none of them came back alive.
لكن لم يعد أي منهم حيا.
They might have died
ربما ماتوا
at his hands.
على يديه.
So
لذا
this time, even if you
هذه المرة ، حتى لو كنت
turn the city upside down,
قلب المدينة رأسًا على عقب ،
you'll have to find him for me!
عليك أن تجده بالنسبة لي!
Yes.
نعم.
How is Young Master lately?
كيف هو السيد الشاب في الآونة الأخيرة؟
He has been working hard.
لقد كان يعمل بجد.
I heard
سمعت
he wants to learn mapping.
يريد أن يتعلم رسم الخرائط.
It seems
يبدو
he has learned his lesson
لقد تعلم درسه
and is ready to be a new person.
وعلى استعداد لأن تكون شخصًا جديدًا.
That's great.
ذلك رائع.
As long as I'm here,
طالما أنا هنا ،
and he is a good boy,
وهو ولد جيد ،
he can be
يستطيع أن يكون
a  well-behaved heir.
وريث حسن التصرف.
Bad news!
اخبار سيئة!
Young Master is here to learn mapping again.
السيد الشاب هنا لتعلم رسم الخرائط مرة أخرى.
Slowly.
ببطء.
Hide.
يخفي.
Hurry.
عجل.
[Planning Room]
[غرفة التخطيط]
Young Master is here.
السيد الشاب هنا.
Why is no one welcoming him?
لماذا لا يرحب به أحد؟
Welcome.
أهلا وسهلا.
Welcome, Young Master.
مرحبا سيد الشباب.
Please forgive me
رجائاً أعطني
for not welcoming you in the hallway.
لعدم الترحيب بك في الردهة.
I just heard outside that your planning room
لقد سمعت للتو خارج غرفة التخطيط الخاصة بك
is busy.
مشغول.
Why wasn't there anyone here
لماذا لم يكن هناك أحد هنا
when I arrived?
عندما وصلت؟
You all have been avoiding me, right?
لقد كنتم جميعا تتجنبونني ، أليس كذلك؟
Of course not, Young Master.
بالطبع لا ، سيد الشباب.
The entire planning room is
غرفة التخطيط بأكملها
looking forward to seeing you
نتطلع إلى رؤيتكم
like we long for stars and the moon.
كما نتوق إلى النجوم والقمر.
Stop!
قف!
Where are them?
أين هم؟
We are longing for the stars.
نحن نتوق إلى النجوم.
It's still daytime now.
لا يزال الوقت نهارًا الآن.
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
My young master,
سيدي الشاب ،
in the planning room,
في غرفة التخطيط ،
everyone who has some skills
كل من لديه بعض المهارات
is tortured by you.
تعذب بواسطتك.
No.
رقم.
I mean,
أعني،
you
أنت
are too smart
أذكياء جدا
and too talented.
وموهوب جدا.
We, the ordinary ones, can't teach you.
نحن ، العاديين ، لا يمكننا أن نعلمك.
Don't be so nervous.
لا تكن متوترا جدا.
I just want you to teach me.
أنا فقط أريدك أن تعلمني.
At worst, I can suffer.
في أسوأ الأحوال ، يمكن أن أعاني.
I can't do two things at once.
لا أستطيع أن أفعل شيئين في وقت واحد.
You can't do this and you can't do that.
لا يمكنك فعل هذا ولا يمكنك فعل ذلك.
Do you want our young master
هل تريد سيدنا الشاب
to get one on the street?
للحصول على واحدة في الشارع؟
Good idea!
فكره جيده!
Since ancient times,  the master hand has been hiding on the street.
منذ العصور القديمة ، كانت اليد الرئيسية مختبئة في الشارع.
We will find a good teacher for you.
سنجد لك مدرسًا جيدًا.
The master hand is on the street.
يد السيد في الشارع.
Recruiting from the street?
التجنيد من الشارع؟
Interesting.
مثير للإعجاب.
[Notice]
[يلاحظ]
Recruiting talents.
توظيف المواهب.
We wish to recruit a surveyor
نرغب في توظيف مساح
to help Young Master build Cangyue City.
لمساعدة السيد الشاب في بناء مدينة كانغيو.
[Liaowu Mansion]
[قصر لياوو]
One must be proficient in mapping
يجب على المرء أن يكون بارعا في رسم الخرائط
and feng shui.
وفنغ شوي.
Attractive monthly salary. Food and accommodation included.
راتب شهري جذاب.  وشملت الغذاء والسكن.
Promising career prospects.
آفاق وظيفية واعدة.
There are still people here.
لا يزال هناك أشخاص هنا.
Miss.
يغيب.
5, 000 copper coins.
5.000 قطعة نقدية نحاسية.
No queuing.
لا طابور.
Miss, look.
افتقد النظر.
There are so many people ahead.
هناك الكثير من الناس في المستقبل.
If they were chosen,
إذا تم اختيارهم ،
you would have missed
كنت قد فاتتك
a good chance to reach success by one step.
فرصة جيدة للوصول إلى النجاح بخطوة واحدة.
Miss, please.
ملكة جمال من فضلك.
I'm here early in the morning.
أنا هنا في الصباح الباكر.
When is my turn?
متى جاء دوري؟
Excuse me.
اعذرني.
Miss.
يغيب.
These two...
هذين...
What are they doing?
مالذي يفعلونه؟
You stand here.
انت تقف هنا.
That's too much.
هذا كثير جدا.
Who is she?
من هي؟
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Brother.
أخ.
Don't you just shove me in front of the queue?
ألا تدفعني أمام قائمة الانتظار؟
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
Why don't you line up properly?
لماذا لا تصطف بشكل صحيح؟
Since I took your money,
منذ أن أخذت أموالك ،
I have to let you stand in the front.
لا بد لي من السماح لك بالوقوف في المقدمة.
Leave the rest to me.
اترك الباقي لي.
What?
ماذا؟
We've been waiting for so long.
لقد كنا ننتظر طويلا.
Come down now.
تعال الآن.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Get in the back!
ارجع في الخلف!
Line up at the back!
اصطف في الخلف!
Line up.
اصطفوا.
Are you all crazy?
هل أنت مجنون؟
You're crazy!
انت مجنون!
What do you mean by jumping the queue?
ماذا تقصد بتخطي قائمة الانتظار؟
Why are you cursing at me?
لماذا تشتمني؟
Let me ask you.
دعني أسألك.
In this big world,
في هذا العالم الكبير ،
is this your land?
هل هذه ارضك
What do you mean!
ماذا تقصد!
Go away.
يبتعد.
Miss,
يغيب،
if you are satisfied,
إذا كنت راضيًا ،
please promote it for me.
يرجى الترويج لها بالنسبة لي.
My name is
اسمي هو
Scalper.
المستغل.
Young Master,
المعلم الصغير،
don't make it hard for yourself.
لا تجعل الأمر صعبًا على نفسك.
Let's get married.
دعنا نتزوج.
Marry you?
أتزوجك؟
I won't believe it!
لن أصدق ذلك!
In such a big city,
في مثل هذه المدينة الكبيرة ،
I can't find
لا أجد
a suitable candidate.
مرشح مناسب.
Go on.
تابع.
Next.
التالي.
If I do it now,
إذا فعلت ذلك الآن ،
I might not be able to kill him in one move.
قد لا أتمكن من قتله بحركة واحدة.
Jiang Chaoxi always has bodyguards at his side.
جيانغ تشوكسي دائما لديه حراس شخصيون إلى جانبه.
It seems that I have to find a way
يبدو أنني يجب أن أجد طريقة
to stay by his side
للبقاء بجانبه
and find another chance.
وتجد فرصة أخرى.
Why is there a woman?
لماذا توجد امرأة؟
Miss,
يغيب،
we're not hiring maids today.
نحن لا نوظف خادمات اليوم.
You can come next time.
يمكنك أن تأتي في المرة القادمة.
I'm here to apply for the surveyor position.
أنا هنا لتقديم طلب لشغل منصب مساح.
The notice said
قال الإشعار
the candidate needs to know mapping.
يحتاج المرشح إلى معرفة رسم الخرائط.
But you didn't say you only recruit men.
لكنك لم تقل أنك تجند الرجال فقط.
A girl
فتاة
knows mapping?
يعرف التخطيط؟
Zhu Wen, test her.
تشو ون ، اختبرها.
Let me ask you.
دعني أسألك.
If there is no long bamboo stick,
إذا لم يكن هناك عصا طويلة من الخيزران ،
how should we measure the depth of water?
كيف نقيس عمق الماء؟
You should tie a hammer
يجب عليك ربط المطرقة
to a rope of fine yarn
إلى حبل من الغزل الناعم
and throw it under the water.
ورميها تحت الماء.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
how long is the rope in the water, how deep is the water.
ما هو طول الحبل في الماء ، ما مدى عمق الماء.
Let me ask again.
اسمحوا لي أن أسأل مرة أخرى.
we can't construct without mapping.
لا يمكننا البناء بدون رسم الخرائط.
What should we do to draw a map?
ماذا يجب ان نفعل لرسم خريطة؟
According to the map of Yugong,
وفقًا لخريطة Yugong ،
there are six elements to making maps.
هناك ستة عناصر لعمل الخرائط.
Ratio, accuracy, milage,
النسبة والدقة والمسافة المقطوعة
level, slope, and tortuosity.
المستوى والمنحدر والتعرج.
I prefer mapping to scale.
أنا أفضل رسم الخرائط على نطاق واسع.
More precise.
أكثر دقة.
Keep her.
احتفظ بها.
Thank you, Young Master.
شكرا لك أيها السيد الشاب.
Congratulations on entering the second round.
تهانينا لدخولك الدور الثاني.
As a surveyor,
كمساح ،
one needs not only
لا يحتاج المرء فقط
professional skills,
مهارات احترافية،
but a healthy body.
لكن الجسم السليم.
Let's begin.
هيا نبدأ.
Let me see
دعني أرى
your strength.
قوتك.
You can try to lift
يمكنك محاولة الرفع
the most weight you can bear.
أكبر وزن يمكنك تحمله.
Who lifts the highest can stay.
من يرفع أعلى يمكنه البقاء.
Come on! Come on!
هيا!  هيا!
I'm afraid
أنا خائف
I can't beat them.
لا أستطيع التغلب عليهم.
It seems that I need to pull some tricks.
يبدو أنني بحاجة لأخذ بعض الحيل.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Young Master,
المعلم الصغير،
the most important thing for me
أهم شيء بالنسبة لي
is to shoulder the responsibility
هو تحمل المسؤولية
to help you build Cangyue City.
لمساعدتك في بناء مدينة كانغيو.
You see.
هل ترى.
This responsibility
هذه المسؤولية
is so heavy.
ثقيل جدا.
Fine.
بخير.
I like what you said.
أحب ما قلته.
Stay.
يقضي.
Thank you, Young Master.
شكرا لك أيها السيد الشاب.
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
Who threw it?
من رماها؟
Did you throw it?
هل رميته؟
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
Bad news.
اخبار سيئة.
There are water snake caves under Dongze Lake.
توجد كهوف ثعابين مائية تحت بحيرة Dongze.
So the foundation of the Ancestral Temple is unstable.
لذا فإن أساس معبد الأجداد غير مستقر.
Lord Song sent me to ask you
أرسلني لورد سونغ لأسألك
how to deal with it.
كيفية التعامل معها.
Why are you asking me
لماذا انت تسالني
how to deal with it?
كيفية التعامل معها؟
Just build the temple
فقط قم ببناء المعبد
in another place.
في مكان آخر.
Young Master,
المعلم الصغير،
the Ancestral Temple worships the ancestors of the Jiang family.
يعبد معبد الأجداد أسلاف عائلة جيانغ.
We can't simply change the site.
لا يمكننا ببساطة تغيير الموقع.
Trees move to death; people move to life.
تتحرك الأشجار حتى الموت ؛  ينتقل الناس إلى الحياة.
Maybe they'll thank me
ربما يشكرونني
if we change the site.
إذا قمنا بتغيير الموقع.
Go burn some incense
اذهب واحرق بعض البخور
and tell my ancestors that they're moving.
وأخبر أجدادي أنهم يتحركون.
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
Didn't you promise Master
ألم تعد سيدي
to do things well?
لفعل الأشياء بشكل جيد؟
To move ancestral graves,
لنقل قبور الأجداد ،
isn't it too careless
أليس كذلك الإهمال
if we just burn some incense?
إذا قمنا فقط بحرق بعض البخور؟
You're right.
أنت على حق.
I was careless.
لقد كنت مهملا.
You!
أنت!
What's your name?
ما اسمك؟
Yunxi.
يونشى.
how will you find the water snake caves?
كيف ستجد كهوف ثعبان الماء؟
Please wait a moment.
فضلا انتظر لحظة.
You'll know soon.
ستعرف قريبًا.
Human beings and all things are in symbiosis.
البشر وجميع الأشياء في تكافل.
To build houses and the city,
لبناء البيوت والمدينة ،
in addition to understanding the environment and feng shui,
بالإضافة إلى فهم البيئة وفنغ شوي ،
you should also know
يجب أن تعرف أيضًا
the features of nearby plants and animal habits.
ملامح النباتات والعادات الحيوانية القريبة.
If you want to know
إذا أردت أن تعرف
where the water snake caves are,
حيث توجد كهوف ثعبان الماء ،
the easiest way
أسهل طريقة
is to ask the water snakes.
هو أن تسأل ثعابين الماء.
Ask them?
إسألهم؟
Look at the water.
انظر إلى الماء.
Aren't you just feeding snakes?
ألست فقط تطعم الثعابين؟
The west of the lake
غرب البحيرة
is about 17 meters away offshore.
حوالي 17 مترا بعيدا عن الشاطئ.
The buoy is moving now.
العوامة تتحرك الآن.
It means there is no water snake cave there.
هذا يعني أنه لا يوجد كهف ثعبان مائي هناك.
You are really smart.
أنت ذكي حقًا.
Of course.
بالطبع.
I've been smart since I was young.
لقد كنت ذكيا منذ أن كنت صغيرا.
Your trick. Draw a snake out of its hole.
خدعتك.  ارسم ثعبانًا من جحره.
I've already thought of it.
لقد فكرت بالفعل في ذلك.
I was just testing your ability.
كنت فقط أختبر قدرتك.
So, we can lay the foundation of the Ancestral Temple
لذلك ، يمكننا وضع الأساس لمعبد الأجداد
20 meters away
على بعد 20 مترا
from the west shore.
من الشاطئ الغربي.
Are you sure this is the right distance?
هل أنت متأكد من أن هذه هي المسافة الصحيحة؟
My eyes are the ruler.
عيناي هي الحاكم.
If you don't believe me,
إذا كنت لا تصدقني ،
you can ask someone to measure it.
يمكنك أن تطلب من شخص ما قياسه.
I just
أنا فقط
praised you a little.
أشاد بك قليلا.
And you want to create an opportunity
وتريد خلق فرصة
for me to save you?
بالنسبة لي لإنقاذك؟
-Young Master, I... -Don't worry.
- السيد الشاب ، أنا ... - لا تقلق.
I'll give you a chance later.
سأعطيك فرصة لاحقا.
Here.
هنا.
Yes.
نعم.
Look here.
انظر هنا.
Okay.
تمام.
This is a construction site.
هذا موقع بناء.
How dare he bring a woman here for fun?
كيف يجرؤ على إحضار امرأة هنا من أجل المتعة؟
He is really an useless young master.
إنه حقا سيد شاب عديم الفائدة.
Lord Song.
لورد سونغ.
Lord Song!
أغنية الرب!
He's here.
إنه هنا.
Oh my god.
يا إلهي.
Here.
هنا.
Here's your chance.
ها هي فرصتك.
Seize it.
اغتنمها.
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
How's your ride, Young Master?
كيف هي رحلتك أيها السيد الصغير؟
You came in person.
أتيت شخصيًا.
You should tell me ahead of time next time,
يجب أن تخبرني في وقت مبكر في المرة القادمة ،
so that I can welcome you.
حتى أرحب بكم.
I don't need it.
لا أحتاجه.
I and my beauty
أنا وجمالي
just feed the fish,
فقط اطعم السمك ،
and we find out
ونكتشف ذلك
where the water snake caves are.
حيث توجد كهوف ثعبان الماء.
Listen.
استمع.
Just lay the foundation
فقط ضع الأساس
20 meters offshore
20 مترا بعيدا عن الشاطئ
to the west.
الى الغرب.
No, Young Master.
لا ، السيد الشاب.
What is the ground
ما هي الارض
for laying the foundation there?
لوضع الأساس هناك؟
What ground?
أي أرضية؟
My words are the ground.
كلماتي هي الأرض.
Don't you forget to mention
لا تنسى أن تذكر
how hard I work for the temple
كم أعمل بجد في المعبد
in front of my father
امام والدي
and my uncle.
وعمي.
Understood.
مفهوم.
-Understand? -Yes, yes, sir.
-يفهم؟  -نعم نعم سيدي.
Yes.
نعم.
Okay, you may leave.
حسنًا ، يمكنك المغادرة.
Okay.
تمام.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
Young Master is here!
السيد الشاب هنا!
Cheer up!
ابتهج!
Hurry up.
عجلوا.
Don't stand in my way.
لا تقف في طريقي.
This way.
من هنا.
Hurry up.
عجلوا.
Hurry up!
عجلوا!
I'm going over there.
انا ذاهب هناك.
Alrighty.
حسنًا.
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
The job I applied for
الوظيفة التي تقدمت لها
is a surveyor to assist you,
مساح لمساعدتك ،
not a beauty who plays with you.
ليس الجمال الذي يلعب معك.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
What is your purpose
ما هو هدفك
of approaching me?
من الاقتراب مني؟